<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0">

<channel>
  <title>harrisonmalone.info</title>
  <link>http://harrisonmalone.info</link>
  <description>I talk, write and code.</description>
  
    <item>
    <title>Reminders</title>
    <link>http://www.harrisonmalone.info/posts/reminders</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">/posts/reminders</guid>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;I&#8217;m using Siri more than ever in my general workflow. Why you might ask? Well I use Siri all the time to set reminders. Yes the same reminders app which for most people is tucked away in a folder or deleted completely to save storage. That shitty reminders app as it&apos;s often known.&lt;/p&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;Luckily, because Siri does reminders really well you barely have to even visit this ancient relic of Apple design. Siri itself is the reminders app. Built in is this secret intuitive reminders system which I feel is underrated and more likely that not (I don&#8217;t have Apple usage stats) barely used. It&#8217;s simple software and it just works. It&#8217;s Apple doing what it does best. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You might not be as forgetful as me but I&#8217;m sure most people have some kind reminders system. Writing on your hand for example. I set reminders 80% of the time by typing to Siri (oh and seriously &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.igeeksblog.com/how-to-enable-type-to-siri-in-ios-11/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;enable type to Siri&lt;/a&gt; already). On iOS all you have to do is hold down the home button (side button for iPhone X) and type in your reminder. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An example of a highly used type to Siri reminder for me is &#8220;remind me to put the washing on the line at 3PM&#8221;. From this string Siri automatically figures out that the message you want printed is &#8220;put the washing on the line&#8221; and to set a push notification up for 3PM. Simple and fast. Remembering the prompt structure is the trickiest bit (remind me to [do something] at [time/date]) but it becomes second nature after a few attempts. I also set reminders on OS X using the same prompt and by activating Siri with the command-space hot key.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I must mention here that the iPad type to Siri is particularly nice. I think this was an &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/viticci&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;@viticci&lt;/a&gt; tweet but it was something along the lines of type to Siri on iPad is like having a smart command line. I love this ability to type in one word and get something useful back.   &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, I also use my voice to set reminders and this will generally be when I&#8217;m driving or if I have my hands full (hey Siri works even if you have your phone in your pocket). I actually think learning the type to Siri commands allows you to use your voice better. Siri will work better when you as the user learn how to speak the Siri language. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I mentioned before that you don&#8217;t need to even go into the shitty reminders app. By simply imputing the string &#8220;reminders&#8221; to Siri you get your list of reminders and you can check them from within the Siri interface. Useful huh. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This use of Siri also inspired me to jump back on the iCal bandwagon (or is it just called Apple Calendars now?). It&apos;s weird because I still think Google Calendar&#8217;s UX is far better. It&#8217;s prettier, uses Google Maps and not Apple Maps and has a reminder system integrated within it.  But and it&#8217;s a big but... notifications can be a bit dodgy for Google apps on iOS and you don&#8217;t get Siri integration.   &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I liked how you could set reminders from within both Google Inbox and Google Calendar but there was serious problems with the way notifications for desktop and notifications for iOS talked to each other. If you set up a reminder on one it wouldn&#8217;t appear on the other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can type to Siri &#8220;schedule lunch with Mike on Friday at 4PM&#8221; and it makes a one hour event. If I then set up a calendar notification, I know I&#8217;ll get a notification across all my devices (Mac and iOS). Reliable push notifications is the biggest part of this puzzle for me. Even if some things could be improved on both Apple and Google&#8217;s behalf, Apple wins out because of this notification reliability.   &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully Apple revamps the design of Calendar and Reminders at the next WWDC as it&#8217;s severely needed. They spoke about these problems on &lt;a href=&quot;https://overcast.fm/+CdSpFx40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;ATP&lt;/a&gt; this week, as well as floating the idea of having a Reminders Pro option, similar to what Apple have done with &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.apple.com/en-au/HT204987&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Notes&lt;/a&gt;. I like this Pro idea a lot. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Siri gets bashed all the time and rightly so, but I don&#8217;t understand why Apple doesn&#8217;t sell something like this &#8220;set reminder&#8221; voice command more in say an advertisement for HomePod or AirPods. It&#8217;s a great feature; just most people don&#8217;t know about it. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>Code</title>
    <link>http://harrisonmalone.info/posts/code</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/posts/code</guid>
    <description>
    	&lt;p&gt;I&#8217;m finally doing something that I&#8217;ve wanted to do for about 3 years. I&#8217;m coding. I&#8217;m focussed on learning a programming language (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ruby-lang.org/en/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Ruby&lt;/a&gt;) and making gains. It&#8217;s not easy. Nothing in life is however at least I&#8217;m enjoying the shit out of what I&#8217;m working on. The feeling that I&#8217;m building something; building a product and building up my own knowledge feels powerful. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;For a long time I&#8217;ve felt listless and unskilled. I&#8217;ve applied for job after job, never really knowing what I was doing. Should I apply for copywriting, journalism or research jobs? I did a Bachelor of Arts at a great university so I know I&#8217;m qualified to do a lot of work out there but its been tough finding the right fit.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The thing is I hated my degree. I never hustled if I didn&#8217;t need to hustle. I didn&#8217;t network and didn&#8217;t really learn from the lecturers. I just did the course work and passed. That's a fault on my behalf and it's affecting my ability to find my feet career wise now. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;In the back of my mind I know I'll find work eventually. It'll be shitty but you have to start somewhere. But then there's also been this itch. It's deep down in my guts and my heart. This feeling that that I need to go back to school to learn how to code and develop. Yes, it&#8217;s this buzz thing and people are saying that everyone should learn how to code. But thats not the only reason why I&#8217;m interested in it. I&#8217;m interested in it because I&#8217;m fucking actually interested. I&#8217;ve always loved talking and writing about computers and software. I&#8217;ve loved playing around and tinkering with code. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;So I&#8217;m doing something about this itch. Finally. I&#8217;m going to go do a short course coding bootcamp at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lewagon.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Le Wagon&lt;/a&gt;. I chose Le Wagon because I like everything they talk about in their FAQs section and it seems like far less bullshit than somewhere like &lt;a href=&quot;https://generalassemb.ly&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;General Assembly&lt;/a&gt;. You learn Ruby and SQL. You learn more of the advanced CSS stuff (flexbox, grid). You get to pitch an idea. It&#8217;s everything I&#8217;ve wanted to do and more.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I know I won&#8217;t be getting a developer or product job fresh out of the course. That&#8217;s impossible. But what I will make sure I get out of it is connections. Friendships with people in a similar boat to me, with similar interests and dreams. That&#8217;s really what I lacked from my university experience. Everyone was all over the shop in an Arts degree. There was no structure.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;It&#8217;s expensive to go out and do the course (10k) but I think it&#8217;s worth every penny. Life&#8217;s too short not to take chances and risks like this. And I need to do something about my career here and now because fuck; it&#8217;s better wasting some money than being depressed on the couch and numb with stresses from finding work. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I feel like I&#8217;m getting a real hold of what I want. Making my own choices and being my own man. I&#8217;m a grown up and if I fail then so be it. It&#8217;s all on me. &lt;/p&gt;
    </description>
  </item>
  
</channel>
</rss>